<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>JENNIFER EMERY</title><link href="https://jnemery.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://jnemery.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://jnemery.github.io/</id><updated>2017-03-03T17:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Chicago 2016 Food Inspections</title><link href="https://jnemery.github.io/chicago-2016-food-inspections.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-03T17:00:00+01:00</published><author><name>Jennifer Emery</name></author><id>tag:jnemery.github.io,2017-03-03:chicago-2016-food-inspections.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the state of Chicago inspected 144,003 different places that were serving food.
Of these 144,003 different places, there were 442 different facility types. These included grocery stores, restaurants, school cafeterias, bars, and many more different kinds of facilities. Upon inspecting the food inspection data further, however, there were a lot of repeated facility types that would be counted as two “different” places when in reality they were the same type of facility. For example, one type would be listed as “School” while another listed as “SCHOOL”. This would cause School and SCHOOL to be incorrectly listed as two different facility types, likely driving up the number of different facility types inspected up to 442. Because of this, I suspect that the true number of different inspected facility types was closer to 400.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="map" src="/images/dataScience/frequency_of_restaurants.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the above photo, you can easily see the location of where facilities were inspected the most in Chicago. This image shows that most inspected places were in the south most part of Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the food inspections, facilities were rated on their risk levels. A risk level rating of 1 meant they were at high risk, while a risk level rating of 3 meant that they were at low risk.
The average overall risk level of all the facilities in Chicago was around a 1.4, which means that most of the places are at a high risk and scored poorly on their health inspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="RiskLevel" src="/images/dataScience/averageRiskLevel.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few different zip codes in Chicago, and I was curious to see if there was a correlation between the risk level and where the facilities were located.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="riskByZip" src="/images/dataScience/riskCountByZip.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you can see… Not much. Most of the high risk areas seem to be around the 60610 zip code, however they are all squished together so much it is hard to tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="riskByZip2" src="/images/dataScience/plotbyRisk.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a different way to look at it, and it is easier to see where the high risk zip codes are. They start popping up just around zip code 60500, and really ramp up around zip code 60600. This also shows where the low risk facilities were located by zip code, and as you can see it seems like they were in the very same areas where the high risk facilities were located! Because of this, I don't feel comfortable jumping to any conclusions about a correlation between facility type and where it was located by zip code.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Docker</title><link href="https://jnemery.github.io/docker.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-22T17:35:00+01:00</published><author><name>Jennifer Emery</name></author><id>tag:jnemery.github.io,2017-01-22:docker.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At my current company, we are starting to use Docker. This has sparked quite a bit of curiosity into me as I want to 
know about the product we are soon to be using. What does one do when they want to learn more about a topic? That's easy!
You Google it! Off I go...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"Docker is the world's leading software containerization platform"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Containerization? I know I've heard of it before, but this is going to take a little more sleuthing to be 100% comfortable
about. After a bit more searching, I found a nice article
&lt;a href="http://www.cio.com/article/2924995/enterprise-software/what-are-containers-and-why-do-you-need-them.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; that
explains that containerization allows you to get software to
run reliably when moved from one environment to the next. 
Containers have everything an application needs to run, which
makes that application able to run on different systems with no
need to worry about differences in Operating Systems. This article
also goes in to talk about the difference between containerization
and virtualization. After more explination than I will go into
here, they explain that a container ends up being about tens of 
megabytes in size, while a virtual machine can end up being 
several gigabytes in size. I feel comfortable moving on from what 
containerization is, so onto more about Docker!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker has a nice visual about comparing containers and virtual 
machines! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="VM" src="/images/docker/Docker_VM.png" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Docker" src="/images/docker/Docker_Docker.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this diagram alone, it seems like virtual machines are much 
more clunky than Docker. I am enjoying what I am seeing so far... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should probably be doing homework instead of researching what 
Docker is, so I will call it quits for now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next time!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>My First Post</title><link href="https://jnemery.github.io/my-first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-22T16:40:00+01:00</published><author><name>Jennifer Emery</name></author><id>tag:jnemery.github.io,2017-01-22:my-first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first post!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>